FUYUAN LYU

845 Sherbrooke St W, Montreal, Quebec

fuyuan.lyu@mail.mcgill.com

silentspring2.github.io

1

SUMMARY

I'm currently a Ph.D. student at McGill University. I am fortunate to be advised by Prof Jin Guo and Prof Xue Liu.

Prior to joining McGill, I got my bachelor's degree of Computer Science and Zhiyuan Honour Degree of Engineering from Shanghai Jiao Tong University(SJTU). I was advised by Prof Li Jiang and Prof Xiaokang Yang.

My research interest lies in the intersection between Machine Learning, Software Engineering and Internet of Things.

EDUCATION

- PhD, Computer Science, McGill University, 2024(exp)
- BEng, Computer Science, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2019
- Zhiyuan Honor Degree for BEng, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2019

PUBLICATIONS

Fuyuan Lyu, Shien Zhu, Weichen Liu, "Cross-filter compression for CNN inference acceleration", ArXiv preprint

Ke Li, Junzheng Wu, Huanlai Xing, **Fuyuan Lyu**, Pingzhi Fan and Chao Zhang, Mobility-Aware Online Content Caching for Vehicular Networks based on Deep Reinforcement Learning, submitted to IEEE Internet of Things Journal.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

McGill University Sept 2019 to present

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Jin Guo & Prof. Xue Liu

- Proposed to study the transferability of pruned model
- Proposed to design hardware-aware pruning methods

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Li Jiang

Built an light-weight end-to-end solution that support pruned neural network on edge devices

Nanyang Technological University

Aug 2018 to Feb 2019 Advisor: Prof. Weichen Liu

Feb 2019 to Aug 2019

Research Assistant

• Explored CNN spatial-adjunct layer property and proposed cross-filter acceleration method.

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Jun 2017 to Feb 2018

Research Assistant Advisor: Prof. Xiaokang Yang

- Explored the possibility of more realistic cloth transfer by generating and transferring structure in 3D dimension.
- Designed a specific generative adversarial network to animate cartoon figures.

TEACHING AND MENTORING EXPERIENCE

- 2020 Winter COMP303 Teaching Assistant
- Reviewer of Transaction on Service Computing

AWARDS

- Wolfe Fellowship in Sci & Tech, 2019-2022
- Grad Excellence Award of McGill University, 2019-2022
- Zhiyuan Honor Degree of Engineering of Shanghai Jiao Tong University(1%), 2019
- Zhiyuan Oversea Research Scholarship (1st class) of Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2019
- Zhiyuan Outstanding Student Scholarship of Shanghai Jiao Tong University(5%), 2019
- Microsoft Intelligence Award , awarded to 4/438 participants in the 1st HACKxFDU Hackathon, 2016.

SKILLS

Software Python, C++, Java

Languages English: professional proficiency. Mandarin: native.